Guide to the Records of Office of the Chancellor RG.3.0.1
New York University Archives
- Series I
  - Council Minutes, 1868 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Salaries, 1868 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Bills and vouchers (with information about salaries); list of University expenses, 1868-1869 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Report to Regents: Reports on instruction (full report missing), 1868-1869 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Letters from James McCosh (President of Princeton) to Howard Crosby, Aug. 16 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Chancellor's Report, 1869 Dec. 2 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence including: Charles Taylor, James Baird, Charles Meyer, Rev. George R. Entlers, J. Draper, F.J. Campbell; and list of graduates from the Medical Department; letters, commencement ticket, clippings about the worth of the College of the City of New York in light of its enormous expenses; list of commencement awards, 1869 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Law Department material including a recommendtion of law students for graduation, 1869 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Minutes of the Council; Report of Inspectors of Election; and Report of Committee on Honorary Degrees, 1869 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Bills and vouchers (with information about salaries), 1869 (Box 10)
  - Letter from Isaac Ferris to Howard Crosby, 1870 July. 3 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Letter from John W. Draper to Howard Crosby about a meeting to discuss Draper's plan for reorganization of the University, 1870 July. 22 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Letter from John W. Draper to Howard Crosby about the "matter of Chancellorship", 1870 Sept. 23 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Letter from William R. Martin to Clerke, 1870 Nov. 14 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Photocopy of article from the Evening Post citing the achievements of Ferris, 1870 Nov. 16 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence including: Dr. Barnard, Charles Butler, John W. Draper, J.C. Green, and a lettr from the Committee of Council of NYU to Howard Crosby, a letter from Crosby to the Committee of Council, and Crosby's acceptance as Chancellor; also a list of Medical Graduates; Reports of the Committee on changes in the curriculum; the notice of re-election of Dr. Crosby as Chancellor; inauguration, and the inauguration remarks of John Taylor Johnston; note, letters, clippings about Ferris' resignation; Ferris' resignation and Farewell address to the Council, 1870 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Report to Regents (year ending Sept. 19) [Missing as of 8/14/89], 1870-1871 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Law Department material including subscriptions and expenses, 1870-1871 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Letter from James Parton to Howard Crosby (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Letters from John T. Johnston to Howard Crosby, Apr. 5 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence of John W. Draper and Howard Crosby, May. 20 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Plan for Departments of Science and Arts, 1871-1872, 1871 June. 22 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Letter from Noah Porter (President of Yale) to Howard Crosby, 1871 Oct. 20 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Chancellor's Report, 1871 Oct. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Letter from John W. Draper to William R. Martin, 1871 Nov. 3 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence including: letters from Whitelaw Reid (of the NY Tribune) concerning lecturing at NYU about journalism; lists of candidates for graduation in the Medical Department; and Report on attendance by each member of the Council; notes about Ferris' compact with the University Council, letter recommending that a student be allowed to join Delta Phi fraternity, 1871 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Law Library material concerning books, 1871 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Minutes of the Council including votes by proxy for annual election of Council and Finance Committee Rules, 1871 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Report to Regents (year ending Sept. 17), 1871-1872 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Lecture notice for "Education Free" a program for 1871-1872 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Letter from Henry E. Davies to William R. Martin, 1872 Jan. 23 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Photocopy of J.W. Draper letter to William A. Butler concerning Morse and invention of the telegraph (See: Box 14, fldr. 20 for original), 1872 Apr. 5 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - L.D. Gale's "Historic Facts concerning Morse's Electro Mag Telegraph", 1872 Apr. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Letter from J.W. Draper to Howard Crosby with resolutions to the Council, 1872 Oct. 28 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence includes: letters about finances, salaries, and the finance Committee; letters from Ward and Ogden about renting University Building for stores and about alterations to the building; resolution for candidates for graduation in the Medical Dept., 1872 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1872 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Report to Regents (year ending Sept. 15), 1872-1873 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Programs of lectures by faculty, 1872-1873 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Graduating candidates from the Medical Department, 1872-1873 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Letter from D.R. Jaques to William R. Martin, 1873 Apr. 1 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Address at funeral of Isaac Ferris, 1873 June. 20 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Report on Law Department, 1873 Nov. 21 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Report on Medical Department, 1873 Dec. 1 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Suggestions of the Medical Department, 1873 Dec. 1 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Letter from John W. Draper to Howard Crosby, 1873 Dec. 24 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence; resolution of candidates for degrees in the Medical Dept.; financial statements; minutes; and a circular about an endowment for the University; clippings about Ferris' resignation from the chancellorship of the Univ., Ferris' obituaries, 1873 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Law Department material, 1873 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Records and minutes of the Council, 1873 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, 1874 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1874 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Alteration of University Building with letters from F. Julius Munckwitz (b.1829-d.1902, who was a Fellow of the American Institute of Architects, 1859-1869, and on the Central Park Staff, 1859-1885), 1874-1875 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Budget request from Howard Crosby to William R. Martin, 1874-1875 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1875 Feb. 19 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Faculty of Law Report, 1875 May. 10 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1875 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence with Royal College of Surgeons, Apr. 3 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence including: letters from Henry Draper to M.K. Jesup; and a Report of the Committee of the Faculty, appointed on July 25th (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence of the Medical Dept.; and candidates for graduation in the Medical Dept., 1876 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Report on the Dept. of Labor, 1877 Feb. 5 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - "Copy of papers in proceedings taken by the University of the City of New York and by William B. Maclay and William A. Wheelock for authority to subject lien of Mortgage...", 1877 Feb. 12 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence including letters from Jesup and Jesup to Members of the University Council, 1877 May. 29 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Medical Dept. tax on graduation fees, 1877 Oct. 27 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence; list of names of M.D. degrees; and honorary degrees conferred by the University, 1877 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence; list of candidates for graduation in the Medical Dept.; petition for conferral of honorary degree to Dr. Edward Bermingham; payment of salaries in funded coupons lent R.R. Co. of N.J.; and Alumni endowment fund record, 1878 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1879 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Report to Regents, year ending Sept. 14, 1880, 1879-1880 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence; clippings and debate on political affairs in which Univ. students participated, 1880 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Circulars, 1881 Feb.-1881 Mar. (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Printed material of the Council, faculty, and administration pertaining to the "Crisis of 1881" (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Material relating to proposal to dissolve academic; article about Ferris published in The University Quarterly, clippings about criticism of Chancellor Crosby, 1881 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Letter of Benjamin N. Martin to Charles Butler, 1881 (?) (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Subscribers of record as of Oct. 10, 1882, 1882 Oct. 10 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence including letter to members of the members of the Council; may 14th draft of John Bigelow to Charles Butler of memorial recounting accomplishments of the University and future prospects; Council Memorial, 1883 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Printed items; clippings about the University's 50th Commencement; clippings about amendments to the Charter of the University, 1883 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Letter from William R. Martin to Charles Butler, 1884 Jan. 1 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Printed Items, 1885 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Resolution of Council for recommendation for honorary degree to Ebenezer A. Johnson, 1888 May. 7 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Letter from William S. Opdyke (Secretary of the Council) to Ernest H. Crosby informing Crosby of his election as Professor in the Law Dept. of a new chair, 1890 Nov. 21 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence including a letter to Faculty on behalf of M. Daniel E. Megio (?) from W. Belden, from W. Belden Jr., Auley?, and C.S. Conkling; letter from Doumas (son of Robert Ogden) to Rev. C. Mason; letter to Ferris from the friends of David Crawford; letter from G.F. Bacon to Chancellor Mathews; letter from E.D. Smith to Ferris; letter from Ferris to Vermilye; and a letter to R.B. Palton, the Librarian. Also included are particulars of the Chinese curiosities and coins; a note to Council; printed notice of professors' fees; and miscellaneous notes of salaries and fees, undated (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Minutes Book of the Building Committee, 1833-1838 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Scholarship forms, 1838 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Bank book, 1854-1856 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Ferris' bankbook, 1858 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Catalog from Chancellor's Desk, 1860 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Chancellor's Report and Report to Regents, 1861-1869 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Printed duplicates, 1881-1885 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Albert Gallatin letter, 1831 Jan. 10 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Francis Lieber to J. Delafield letter, 1831 Feb. 13 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Photocopy of Incorporation of the University of the City of New York, 1831 Apr. 18 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Copy of the survey site of original (University) building, 1833 June. 18 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Seth Geer from NYU, 1833 June-1836 May (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - List of professors, their dept.'s, and salaries, 1833 Nov. 5 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Salisbury loan and mortgage, 1834 Feb.-1834 June. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Journal of Commerce-clipping, 1835 Feb. 13 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - NY Commercial Advertising?-clipping, 1835 July. 18 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - NY Daily Advertiser-clipping, 1835 July. 18 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Samuel F.B. Morse letter to Chancellor about conditions of his rented rooms in University Building, 1836 Feb. 1 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Trustees to Samuel F.B. Morse for damages to his property and loss of rent and tuition due to leakage in University Building totalling $48.18 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Bill from William Jackson, Importer of English Books, 1836 Dec. 3 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Fire Insurance Policies, 1837 Jan. 7 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - "Communication of Cyrus Perkins, M.D." about Medical Dept., 1837 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - NY Commerical Advertiser, 1839 June. 7 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - NY Tribune, 1846 Mar. 30 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - NY Herald, 1853 June. 30 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Alumni Subscription book, 1853 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Printed list of professors and instructors, 1857-1858 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Letter from Draper to William A. Butler concerning Morse and the invention of the telegraph, 1872 Apr. 5 (Box 14, Folder 21)